Guide to the Eastern Parkway Coalition records 2007.016
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 1: Subject files, 1952-2007; 1970-2007
  - Haitian Coalition on AIDS cassette tape, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    This cassette tape was produced by the Haitian Coalition on AIDS in June 1988. It is titled "Lan Mó Avéti Pa Touye Kokobe," "This cassette is made possible by a grant from the NYC Dept. of Health."
  - Haiti Projects in Partnership, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 28, Box OS-42, Folder 6)
  - [Haiti advocacy organizations], 1998-2005 (Box 6, Folder 29, Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Gateway [Gateway National Recreation Area], 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Summer Youth Employment Program, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    These folders include garden sketches and plans.
  - Community Gardens, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 4 - 7, Box OS-42, Folder 5)
  - Community Gardens, 1998-2002 (Box 7, Folder 8, Box OS-42, Folder 3)
  - Prospect Place Garden petition, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Eastern Parkway Area Committee - Summer Youth Program - Sanitation, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - [Museum/Art censorship], 1999 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - [Community Gardens and Parks], 1996-2006 (Box 7, Folder 12 - 13)
  - [Brooklyn - music and tourism], 1979, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Franklin Avenue Shuttle Garden, 1979-2001 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    This file includes photographs and garden plans.
  - Underfunding of Black organizations, 1976-1978 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Greenthumb NYC, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Landmarks Preservation Commission, 1978-1983 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    This file includes Community Board District 8 city program and project review.
  - [Franklin Avenue Shuttle and other subway issues], 1981-1991 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - First Annual Conference on NYC Public Transit, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - [Community Board 8 committees - Parks and NYC public transit], 1981-1994 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - MTA - Rules of Behavior, 1989-1992 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Franklin Avenue Shuttle, 1981-1983 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - [Subway clippings], 1986 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - MTA - Hearing rules, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Summer bus service to Gateway [Gateway National Recreation Area], 1982-1989 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - [Franklin Avenue Shuttle and other subway issues], 1986-1993 (Box 8, Folder 5, Box OS-42, Folder 2)
  - MTA Board, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Community Board 9 - Transportation committee, 1983-1990 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Franklin Avenue Shuttle, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - [Brooklyn Public Library, Brooklyn Museum, Oliver Leeds, citywide strike], 1981-1994 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Scrapbook items, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 10, Box OS-42, Folder 1)
    Includes material relating to Haitians and other Crown Heights community issues; includes photographs
  - [League of Women Voters, representation guide], 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - [Report on Transit Operating Performance in New York State], 1982 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - [New York City Transit Report], 1982 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - [Permanent Citizens Advisory Committee to the MTA reports], 1982 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - ["Analysis of the New York City Policy Toward Demolishing Elevated Transit Lines" thesis], 1981 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - [Metropolitan Transit Authority, Report of the Executive Director], 1983 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - [New York City Transit and Traffic report], 1982 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - [Metropolitan Transportation Authority Report to the Governor], 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - ["Off the Track" public transportation report], 1981 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - [Metropolitan Transit Authority, Strategic Planning Initiative], 1986 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - [New York City Transit Authority Contract Brooklyn East], 1982 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - [New York City Transit Authority Capital Budget], 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - [First Annual Conference on New York City Public Transit], 1982 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - [Metropolitan Transit Authority, Report of the Executive Director], 1982 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - [New York City Transit Authority Operating Budget Proposal], 1987 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - [Metropolitan Transit Authority request for federal financial assistance], 1988 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - [Noise code implementation report], 1984 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - [Straphangers Campaign Reports], 1984-1986 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - [Permanent Citizens Advisory Committee to the MTA report], 1981 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - [New York City Transit Authority Annual Report], 1953-1954 (Box 8, Folder 30, Folder 4)
  - [Franklin Avenue Shuttle study], 1991 (Box 8, Folder 31 - 33)
  - Eastern Parkway Coalition proclamation, 1989 (Box OS-42, Folder 13)
- Series 2: Plans and maps, 1973-1988
  This sub-series contains plans and maps for the reconstruction and redevelopment of Eastern Parkway and other streets in the Prospect Heights and Crown Heights neighborhoods of Brooklyn, dating from 1973 to 1986. The series also includes district maps and plans for playground reconstruction. The plans and maps were produced by the City of New York.
  Most of the materials in this series are stored offsite offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact cbhreference@bklynlibrary.org at least two weeks prior to research visit.
  This series is intellectually arranged by date.
  - Reconstruction of Eastern Parkway plans, 1986 (Folder 1, Folder 2, Folder 3)
    These folders contain New York City Department of Transportation Bureau of Highway Operations blueprints dated October 27, 1986 for the rehabilitation of Eastern Parkway from Washington Avenue to Pitkin Avenue. The Federal Project number is IXA - 504B and the contract number is THCK 170B. The plans cover traffic signals, park removals, lampposts and luminaires, electrical layout, and subway ventilators.
    Related Materials
    Photographs of this project may be held by the New York City Municipal Archives: Accession ACC-1998-016. Unprocessed - RG 046. Department of Transportation Bureau of Highway Operations contractual repair photographs, negatives, and color slides for 1929 to 1982.
  - Eastern Parkway maintenance of traffic general plan, 1986 (Folder 7)
    This material is stored offsite. Please contact library staff for more information.
    This folder includes City of New York Department of Transportation plans, dated October 27, 1986. These blueprints are titled "Maintenance of Traffic - General Plan." Contract number THCK 170B.
  - New York Housing and Development Administration - Crown Heights Community Planning Districts No. 8 and 9 map, 1973 (Box 9)
    This item is not available for research due to its size and fragility.
    This folder contains a Block and Lot Map for Crown Heights Community Planning Districts No. 8 and 9. It was published by the New York Housing and Development Administration with data from the Finance Administration.